<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!-- Copyright 2015 Ankur Sinha <ankursinha@fedoraproject.org> -->

<!-- HOUSEKEEPING, REMOVE THIS COMMENT WHEN THIS GOES UPSTREAM
BugReportURL: rhbz-#
SentUpstream: yyyy-mm-dd
-->

<application>
  <id type="desktop">aqualung.desktop</id>
  <metadata_license>CC0-1.0</metadata_license>
  <summary>Music Player for GNU/Linux</summary>
  <description>
    <p>
        Aqualung is an advanced music player originally targeted at the
        GNU/Linux operating system, today also running on FreeBSD and OpenBSD,
        with native ports to Mac OS X and even Microsoft Windows. It plays
        audio CDs, internet radio streams and podcasts as well as soundfiles in
        just about any audio format and has the feature of inserting no gaps
        between adjacent tracks.  
    </p>
    <p>
        Aqualung is a music player designed from the ground up to provide
        continuous, absolutely transparent, gap-free playback across a variety
        of input formats and a wide range of sample rates thereby allowing for
        enjoying quality music: concert recordings and "non-best-of" albums
        containing gapless transitions between some tracks. (Multiple movements
        long compositions are often broken into separate but gaplessly flowing
        tracks when mastered to CD). 
    </p>
    <p>
        Obvious examples are The Song Remains The
        Same (Led Zeppelin), The Dark Side Of The Moon (Pink Floyd), and
        Yessongs (Yes). Besides the ability to play the music from these
        records without a defect, Aqualung provides high quality sample rate
        conversion, a feature that is essential when building large digital
        music archives containing input sources conforming to various
        standards. Aqualung passed our test – and it will pass yours, too.
    </p>
    <!-- FIXME: Probably needs another paragraph -->
  </description>
  <url type="homepage">http://aqualung.factorial.hu/</url>
  <screenshots>
  <!-- FIXME: Needs an official up to date screenshot -->
      <screenshot type="default">http://aqualung.factorial.hu/screenshots/default.png</screenshot>
      <screenshot type="default">http://aqualung.factorial.hu/screenshots/woody.png</screenshot>
      <screenshot type="default">http://aqualung.factorial.hu/screenshots/metal.png</screenshot>
  </screenshots>
  <!-- FIXME: change this to an upstream email address for spec updates
  <updatecontact>someone_who_cares@upstream_project.org</updatecontact>
   -->
</application>
