<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!-- Copyright 2015 Ankur Sinha <ankursinha AT fedoraproject DOT org> -->

<!-- HOUSEKEEPING, REMOVE THIS COMMENT WHEN THIS GOES UPSTREAM
BugReportURL: rhbz-#
SentUpstream: yyyy-mm-dd
-->

<application>
  <id type="desktop">k9copy.desktop</id>
  <metadata_license>CC0-1.0</metadata_license>
  <name>k9copy</name>
  <summary>Video DVD backup and creation program</summary>
  <description>
    <p>
        K9Copy facilitates several methods for backing up a DVD. The software
        enables direct backup of a single layer DVD-5 provided the user's
        computer has a DVD recorder. Likewise, direct backup of a dual layer
        DVD-9 is possible with a dual layer DVD recorder. K9Copy is able to fit
        the contents of a dual layer DVD-9 onto a single layer DVD-5. The
        interface allows a user to explicitly retain or discard any content
        from the original disc such as video titles, audio tracks, subtitles
        and the DVD menu. 
    </p>
    <p>
        All content selected for backup is compressed to a configurable target
        size (4400 MB by default) and stored on the user's hard drive as either
        an ISO image file or a DVD VIDEO TS folder. K9Copy can either transfer
        the backup data to blank DVD±R media itself or utilize external DVD
        authoring software such as K3b for this task.Furthermore, an ISO image
        file produced by K9Copy can be recorded to DVD by any software on any
        platform capable of recording ISO images to disc. 
    </p>
    <p>
        Functionality for backing up a DVD to a video file (such as MPEG-4)
        rather than a disc also exists in K9Copy : The interface allows the
        user to select the preferred encoder (either MEncoder or FFmpeg) and
        codec for video and audio compression as well as a target file size or
        bit rate for the resulting file. K9Copy includes basic DVD authoring
        capabilities.
    </p>
  </description>
  <url type="homepage">http://k9copy.sourceforge.net/</url>
  <!-- FIXME: Needs an official up to date screenshot 
  <screenshots>
    <screenshot type="default">http://www.upstreamurl.com/screenshots/file.png</screenshot>
  </screenshots>
    -->
  <updatecontact>321eniluap@gmail.com</updatecontact>
</application>

