<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!-- Copyright 2015 Ankur Sinha <ankursinha AT fedoraproject DOT org> -->

<!-- HOUSEKEEPING, REMOVE THIS COMMENT WHEN THIS GOES UPSTREAM
BugReportURL: rhbz-#
SentUpstream: yyyy-mm-dd
-->

<application>
  <id type="desktop">sonic-visualiser-freeworld.desktop</id>
  <metadata_license>CC0-1.0</metadata_license>
  <summary>A program for viewing and exploring audio data</summary>
  <description>
    <p>
        The aim of Sonic Visualiser is to be the first program you reach for
        when want to study a musical recording rather than simply listen to it.
    </p>

    <p>
        The aim of Sonic Visualiser is to be the first program you reach for
        We hope Sonic Visualiser will be of particular interest to
        musicologists, archivists, signal-processing researchers and anyone
        else looking for a friendly way to take a look at what lies inside the
        audio file.
    </p>

    <p>
        The aim of Sonic Visualiser is to be the first program you reach for
        Sonic Visualiser is Free Software, distributed under the GNU General
        Public License (v2 or later) and available for Linux, OS/X, and
        Windows. It was developed at the Centre for Digital Music at Queen
        Mary, University of London. 

        It contains features for the following:
    </p>
    <ul>
        <li>Load audio files in WAV, Ogg and MP3 formats, and view their waveforms</li>
        <li>Look at audio visualisations such as spectrogram views, with interactive adjustment of display parameters</li>
        <li>Annotate audio data by adding labelled time points and defining segments, point values and curves</li>
        <li>Overlay annotations on top of one another with aligned scales, and overlay annotations on top of waveform or spectrogram views</li>
        <li>View the same data at multiple time resolutions simultaneously (for close-up and overview)</li>
        <li>Run feature-extraction plugins to calculate annotations automatically, using algorithms such as beat trackers, pitch detectors and so on</li>
        <li>Import annotation layers from various text file formats</li>
        <li>Import note data from MIDI files, view it alongside other frequency scales, and play it with the original audio</li>
        <li>Play back the audio plus synthesised annotations, taking care to synchronise playback with display</li>
        <li>Select areas of interest, optionally snapping to nearby feature locations, and audition individual and comparative selections in seamless loops</li>
        <li>Time-stretch playback, slowing right down or speeding up to a tiny fraction or huge multiple of the original speed while retaining a synchronised display</li>
        <li>Export audio regions and annotation layers to external files</li>
    </ul>
  </description>
  <url type="homepage">http://www.sonicvisualiser.org/</url>
  <screenshots>
      <screenshot type="default">http://www.sonicvisualiser.org/images/sv-1.0-notetracker.png</screenshot>
      <screenshot type="default">http://www.sonicvisualiser.org/images/sv-1.0-wide.png</screenshot>
      <screenshot type="default">http://www.sonicvisualiser.org/images/sv-1.0-ru.png</screenshot>
      <screenshot type="default">http://www.sonicvisualiser.org/images/sv2-thumb.png</screenshot>
  </screenshots>
  <!-- FIXME: change this to an upstream email address for spec updates
  <updatecontact>someone_who_cares@upstream_project.org</updatecontact>
   -->
</application>

